Otto Soglow Cartoons
Otto Soglow Cartoons
1945-1966
Soglow, Otto, 1900-1975
3 linear ft.
Original cartoons from the comic strip The Little King and original magazine cartoon panels.
149712
Biographical History
Although best known for creating the rotund cartoon character Little King, Otto Soglow was never happy as a cartoonist. Born in Yorkville, New York to a house painter and a cook, he dropped out of high school to pursue his major ambition of acting on Broadway and in Hollywood.
He supported himself through a variety of jobs from errand boy and dishwasher to commercial illustrator. Once he entered the art field, employment was more certain and Soglow expanded his repertoire to magazine illustration. The Little King, a character the artist always claimed "just happened," made a brief appearance in the New Yorker, then became a regular feature and was eventually syndicated by King Features in close to 100 newspapers in the United States and abroad.
Soglow was an organizer of the National Cartoonists Society, served as its president, and received the Society's Founder's Medal in 1966.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Otto Soglow Cartoons collection contains 15 original cartoons from the newspaper comic strip The Little King (1954-1962) and 13 original magazine cartoon panels (most were published in The New Yorker ) (1945-1966).
Arrangement of the Collection
Cartoons are arranged by type in chronological order.
Related Material
Clippings of Ambassador and Little King are located in the
Vernon Greene Papers
.
has collections of more than 150 cartoonists. Please refer to for a complete listing.
Subject and Genre Headings
Art -- Cartoonists; Soglow, Otto, 1900-1975.; King Features Syndicate.; Little king (comic strip); New Yorker (New York, N.Y.: 1925); American wit and humor, Pictorial.; Caricatures and cartoons -- United States.; Cartoonists -- United States.; Comic books, strips, etc. -- United States.; Cartoons (humorous images); Cartoonists.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Inventory
- The Little King cartoons, 15 items; (pen and ink on illustration board, 15 ½ x 23 in.)
  - 1954 (Oversize 1)
    30 May
  - 1955 (Oversize 1)
    17 April; 1 May; 4 Sep; 27 Nov
  - 1956 (Oversize 1)
    12 Feb; 19 Feb; 17 Jun; 23 Sep; 30 Sep
  - 1962 (Oversize 1)
    22 Apr; 22 Jul; 2 Sep; 16 Sep; 21 Oct
  - Undated (Oversize 1)
- Magazine cartoons, 13 items; (pen and ink on illustration board, dimensions vary 11 ½ x 13 in. to 13 ½ x 17 in.)
  - Untitled [martini maker pouring olives], 01/06/1945; (The New Yorker property stamp on back) (Box 1)
  - "My Craziest Dreams Come True" [pull-out bed of nails], 07/20/1958; (American Weekly property stamp on back) (Box 1)
  - Untitled [traffic cop with three faces], 05/23/1959; (published in The New Yorker 5/23/1959) (Box 1)
  - "God Bless Our Home", 09/05/1959; (published in The New Yorker 9/05/1959) (Box 1)
  - "Earn Up to $200,000 a Night" [boxing gloves], 12/05/1959; (published in The New Yorker 12/05/1959) (Box 1)
  - Untitled [dog sled running in circle], 12/12/1959; (published in The New Yorker 12/12/1959) (Box 1)
  - Untitled [man and woman on desert island, "who, me?"], 03/04/1961; (published in The New Yorker 3/04/1961) (Box 1)
  - "There's Something Reminiscent About That Woman" [Abe Lincoln], 04/01/1961; (published in The New Yorker 4/01/1961) (Box 1)
  - "Goodbye, Lover!" [Lover's Leap], 09/08/1962; (published in The New Yorker 9/08/1962) (Box 1)
  - Untitled [escalators], 11/14/1964; (published in The New Yorker 11/14/1964) (Box 1)
  - Untitled [Junior Foods], 01/02/1965; (published in The New Yorker 1/02/1965) (Box 1)
  - Untitled [jack-in-the-box mother], 02/26/1966; (published in The New Yorker 2/26/1966) (Box 1)
  - "Pardon friend - got a minute?" [man in sombrero], undated; ("Jan 20" handwritten in pencil on back, year unknown) (Box 1)